jellybelly.com 2018-09-27

# Privacy Policy | Jelly Belly Candy Company

Last Updated: May 25, 2018 

If you have any questions, please call 1-800-522-3267. 

## Privacy Notice

Thank you for visiting JellyBelly.com. Your privacy is very important to us. We operate this site for enjoyment of general audiences in the United States, and we hope you have a good time. We are committed to the privacy of our visitors from the United States. Please read the following information carefully. It tells you when this notice is effective, what information we collect from you, how we might use it, how you can review or change the personal information you provided to us, how we may change this notice, and the steps we take to ensure that your personal information is protected. 

**If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Notice, please contact us at[webqa@jellybelly.com](mailto:webqa@jellybelly.com).**

**If you are visiting JellyBelly.com from outside the United States, this Privacy Notice does not apply to you. Instead, please review our[International Privacy Notice](http://eu.jellybelly.com/).**

## Agreement to Terms

All activities in which you may engage on this website are voluntary. You are not required to provide any personal information to us unless you choose to access features on this site which require such information. **If you do not agree with the terms of this notice or other terms of use on this website, then you should immediately exit this website without providing us with any of your personally identifiable information and discontinue use of the site.**

## Effective Date and Changes to this Notice

This Privacy Notice is effective as of the date above, and will remain in effect until a new notice supersedes it. We may choose to update this notice at our discretion, so you should check this page periodically as the terms may change from time to time. The most recent version of the notice will be reflected by the "last updated" date noted at the top of the page. In the event of a major change to this Privacy Notice, we will provide a conspicuous message either through the site or via an email address associated with your account informing you of the change. After a reasonable period of time from providing the message, your affirmative consent or continued use of the site will constitute your acknowledgment of the notice in its current version and your understanding of the terms of the notice. 

## Information Collected from You

The majority of this site is offered without collecting any personally identifiable information from our visitors. However, we may collect personal information about you in specific instances described below. We may collect the following personally identifiable information: your name, your billing address, your e-mail address, your shipping address, your phone number, your date of birth, your payment information, your geolocation, and the type of browser and computing device you use. 

Your information is collected when you create an account on the site, place an order, when you voluntarily submit it to enter contests, to request information, or to update your account on the site. We may use your personal information to respond to a request for information or to award prizes or samples. We do not permit third parties, e.g. advertisers, to collect personally identifiable information about your online activity for their own use when you visit our Web Site. 

We may directly contact you with special offers from time to time, but only when you have given us permission to do so. You may decline to receive these offers by leaving unchecked the appropriate box after entering any personal information when you create an account or by clicking the "Email Preference Center" link on your My Account page or in the site’s footer. **You may also change your mind and decline to receive special online offers by following the opt-out link in any of our promotional emails or contacting our Consumer Affairs Department (1-800-JB-BEANS)**. 

## Types of Non-Identifying Information We Collect

We may also collect general information resulting from your activity on the site, including your preferences, insights, and other tendencies. This may include anonymous "traffic data" or tracking information provided by the website’s host or similar provider or collector of such information (i.e., Google Analytics) that does not personally identify you, but may be helpful for marketing purposes or for improving the services we offer. In addition, when you visit our site, we may also log your anonymous IP addresses, a unique identifier for your computer or other access device. This helps us to learn more about areas of the site that are of the most interest to visitors and diagnose problems with our server, to administer our site, or to display the content according to your preferences. 

We also collect non-personal information (type and version of web browser, operating system, and device type) to improve the design and performance of the site. 

We employ other companies to perform functions on our behalf related to the site. Examples include fulfilling orders, delivering packages, sending postal mail and e-mail, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, providing search results and links (including paid listings and links), displaying targeted advertisements and processing credit card payments. They may have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes. You may opt-out from receiving targeted advertisements from AdRoll, one of our vendors, by visiting the NAI website opt-out page 

here: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/> or the DAA opt-out page  
here: <http://www.aboutads.info/> or, for EU users, the EDAA opt-out page  
here: <http://youronlinechoices.eu/>

Your personal data is stored in our Mozu website platform administration dashboard and our dedicated M3 (ERP) servers and in the Azure cloud environment. These servers are located in the United States and are kept secure with PCI compliance protocols, including username and password encryption. 

## A Note to Parents

Jelly Belly is committed to protecting the on-line privacy of children. While this site is operated for the enjoyment of general audiences, we are mindful children may also visit this site. Children are not required to provide any personal information to use any part of this site. We also do not knowingly collect information from children under 13 years of age and they are not permitted to register as a user for the site or to receive communications from us. 

When a consumer emails us, we collect necessary data, which may include e-mail address, street address and telephone number, in order to respond to the consumer’s request. That information is retained in our consumer contact database for internal purposes, but is not shared with third parties for their own use. 

If you have questions or concerns about the Internet and privacy for your child, we encourage you to check out [http://www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/0031-protecting-your-childs-privacy-online.](http://www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/0031-protecting-your-childs-privacy-online)

## Cookies

**The Jelly Belly website uses cookies.** We use cookies to gather non-personal information about your visits to the website and enhance your experience. Cookies track the type of browser, operating system, and Internet service provider you are using and allow us to tabulate the total number of visitors to our site, provide e-commerce functionality including saving product to the shopping cart and facilitating the checkout process, track originating IP address, and track referrals from marketing partners. 

**What is a Cookie?** A cookie is a small string of information that the website you visit transfers to your computer for identification purposes. Cookies can be used to follow your activity on the website and that information helps websites to understand your preferences and improve your website experience. Cookies are also used for such activities as remembering your user name and password, if you use such a feature on this site. 

You may disable the cookie feature on your computer or set it to alert you when cookies are being sent by using the preferences on your browser. If you choose to disable cookies, however, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of JellyBelly.com. 

## How Your Information is Used

We primarily use the personal information you provide and any general information we receive from you to provide products and services to you, including, but not limited to, the following: 

  * To administer a content promotion survey and to provide you with relevant products or services (for example, to deliver a prize you may have won in a contest). 

  * To send you information or materials via e-mail about products, offers, and news we think might interest you. This information may relate to products, offers, and news about us or our licensees or selected commercial partners. We will send you this information only if you have expressly opted-in to receiving e-mails from us. If you no longer wish to receive any e-mails from us, you may unsubscribe by updating your email preferences. 

  * To analyze visits to the website and learn about the interests of visitors in aggregate and also on a personal level to better understand your interests and needs, so we can improve its products and services and deliver the type of content, features and promotions that you are most interested in. 

You may control the frequency with which you receive emails from us (including the complete elimination of promotional email notifications) by visiting the Email Preference Center (<http://www.jellybelly.com/jelly-belly-email-preference-center>). Additionally, you can close your account and indicate that all of your related data should be deleted or, alternatively, indicate that the data can remain but the account be marked as inactive. 

## What Information is Shared and With Whom

Your traffic and transaction information may be shared with our business partners and advertisers on an aggregate and anonymous basis. We may also draw inferences from this information, aggregate this information, and use this information to inform the operation of the website, enhance your website experience, or for any other lawful purpose. Such information shall be governed by this notice in the same manner as any other personal information. 

Other than as described in this Privacy Notice, or as may be necessary to protect the rights, property, and safety of our organization, or others, or as may be necessary to comply with applicable law, we will not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer your personal information or general information to third parties without informing you in advance. However, we may provide some of our services through contractual arrangements with affiliates, services providers, partners and other third parties. Our service partners may use your personal information to operate the website and deliver their services to you. For example, your data may be transferred to website hosting partners and other parties who assist in designing and operating the website, executing services, or helping us analyze collected data. These parties will only use your data for the purpose of carrying out the work as agreed with us and will be required to keep the information confidential. We will encourage our service partners to adopt and post privacy policies. However, the use of your personal information by service partners is governed by the privacy policies of those service partners and is not subject to our control. 

**Jelly Belly uses the following third party services:** Dropbox, Facebook and Facebook Ads, Kibo, Echidna, Google Analytics, Microsoft Azure, PayPal, YouTube Widget, Tealium, AdRoll, Quantcast, CardConnect, Kount, CustomAnswers, PowerReviews, UPS, Brandify, Akamai, Yottaa, Yieldify, Exclusive Concepts, Bing Ads, Google Adwords, Vidi Emi, Bronto, mShopper, Pepperjam and MyBuys/Magnetic/Evergage. This list is representative and is subject to change without notice. 

## Disclosure of Your Information for Security Purposes

Jelly Belly fully cooperates with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our services for illegal activities. We will release personal or general information without your consent for security purposes, when required by law, or to prevent imminent harm to any person or entity. We will disclose personal or general information upon receipt of a court order or subpoena, or to cooperate with a law enforcement investigation, which may include responding to requests and court orders from jurisdictions outside the United States. We reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we in good faith believe to be unlawful, as determined in our sole discretion. 

## Where Your Information is Stored

Your personal data is stored in our Kibo website platform administration dashboard and our dedicated M3 (ERP) servers and in the Azure cloud environment. These servers are located in the United States and are kept secure with PCI compliance protocols, including username and password encryption. 

## How We Protect Your Information and Keep Your Information Secure

In order to protect both the personal information and the general information that we receive from you through the website, we have implemented various security measures, including but not limited to PCI compliance protocols, user-created User Name and Password, and data encryption. 

## Unauthorized Access by Third Parties

Whenever you give out personal information online there is a risk that third parties may intercept and use that information. While we strive to protect your personal information and privacy, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you disclose online. By using this site, you expressly acknowledge and agree that we cannot guarantee the security of any data provided to or received by us through this site and that any personal information, general information, or other data or information received from you through the site is provided at your own risk. 

## Links to Third Parties

The Jelly Belly site may contain hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties. Where this is the case, **we urge you to review the equivalent data protection, privacy and cookie policies available on such websites. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the data protection of privacy practices of third parties in relation to such websites and your use of third party websites is entirely at your own risk**. 

For your convenience and to improve the usage of the website we may insert links to third parties on this site. **This Privacy Notice does not apply to such third party websites.** These links take you outside our service and off our site and are beyond our control. This includes links from partners that may use our logos as part of a co-branding agreement. The sites those links can take you to have their own separate Privacy Notices and although we seek to protect the integrity of the website, we are not responsible for the content and activities of those sites. Your visits and access to such websites is at your own risk. Please note that those other sites may send their own cookies to users, collect data, or solicit personal information. 

## Changes to your Personal Information and Data Retention

The information you provide is kept in perpetuity unless and until you decide to delete it. Deletion is destructive, meaning that it will be completely removed from the active database. For backup purposes, older versions of our database are kept for six months or, in some cases, in perpetuity. We encourage you to promptly update your personal information when it changes. You may also cancel your registration at any time and you may opt out of receiving any promotional e-mails from us. Additionally, you can choose to have all your personal information updated or deleted from our database by notifying us at [webqa@jellybelly.com](mailto:webqa@jellybelly.com). 

## California Do-Not-Track Disclosures

Without changing or revoking any of your privacy protections contained in this Privacy Notice, Jelly Belly respects your privacy, but we do not alter the information we collect or change our services upon receiving "do-not-track" signals, as the term appears in Cal. Bus. & Prof. Code §§ 22575(b)(5). 

## Additional California Privacy Disclosures

We do not share personal information with third parties for their use in marketing as specified under California’s "Shine the Light Act." 

## Questions or Comments

If you have any questions or comments relating to our website or the Privacy Notice, send an e-mail to [webqa@jellybelly.com](mailto:webqa@jellybelly.com). 

28233984  
28362576
